[
    {
        "question": "What is the output of print 0",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "True",
            "Machine dependent",
            "Error"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "False",
        "explanation": "Neither of 0.1, 0.2 and 0.3 can be represented accurately in binary. The round off errors from 0.1 and 0.2 accumulate and hence there is a difference of 5.5511e-17 between (0.1 + 0.2) and 0.3."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is not a complex number?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "k = 2 + 3j",
            "k = complex(2, 3)",
            "k = 2 + 3J"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "k = 2 + 3l",
        "explanation": "l (or L) stands for long."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the type of inf?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "Boolean",
            "Integer",
            "Complex"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Float",
        "explanation": "Infinity is a special case of floating point numbers. It can be obtained by float(\u2018inf\u2019)."
    },
    {
        "question": "What does ~4 evaluate to?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "-4",
            "-3",
            "+3"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "-5",
        "explanation": "~x is equivalent to -(x+1)."
    },
    {
        "question": "What does ~~~~~~5 evaluate to?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "-11",
            "+11",
            "-5"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "+5",
        "explanation": "~x is equivalent to -(x+1)."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is incorrect?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "x = 0b101",
            "x = 0x4f5",
            "x = 19023"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "x = 03964",
        "explanation": "Numbers starting with a 0 are octal numbers but 9 isn\u2019t allowed in octal numbers."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the result of cmp(3, 1)?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "0",
            "True",
            "False"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "1",
        "explanation": "cmp(x, y) returns 1 if x > y, 0 if x == y and -1 if x < y."
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is incorrect?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "float(\u2018inf\u2019)",
            "float(\u2018nan\u2019)",
            "float(\u201956\u2019+\u201978\u2019)"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "float(\u201912+34\u2032)",
        "explanation": "\u2018+\u2019 cannot be converted to a float."
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the result of round(0",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "1.0",
            "2.0",
            "0.0"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "Value depends on Python version",
        "explanation": "The behavior of the"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does 3 ^ 4 evaluate to?",
        "incorrect answers": [
            "81",
            "12",
            "0.75"
        ],
        "correct_answer": "7",
        "explanation": "^ is the Binary XOR operator."
    }
]